When someone asks us “What do you do?” we nearly always reply with our occupation.
别人问我们“你是做什么的？”，我们几乎总是以自己的职业作答。
Work, for many of us, is much more than a job.
对我们很多人来说，工作远不只是一份差事。
It is the defining aspect of our identity.
它是我们身份中起决定性作用的方面。
For many of us it is through our job that we can define ourselves.
对我们很多人来说，正是通过工作，我们才能界定自己。
“Without my job I don’t know who I am” is a sentence that has been uttered on more than a handful of occasions from my office chair.
“没有了工作，我就不知道自己是谁”——坐在办公椅上，这句话我听人说过不止寥寥几次。
Indeed, it can be one of the most challenging aspects I work on with clients who have lost or been forced into changing their jobs.
的确，对于那些失去了工作或被迫换工作的来访者，这可能是我和他们一起处理的最具挑战性的方面之一。
This loss provokes an identity crisis much greater than the loss of the job itself.
这种失去会引发一场身份危机，其严重程度远远超过失去工作本身。
One of the things I have come to understand, however, is that our identity is much more complex than we recognise at first glance.
然而，我逐渐明白的一点是：我们的身份比乍看之下所认识到的要复杂得多。
If we take the time to reflect we might recognise that as well as our work we can also identify as a friend, a spouse, a son or daughter, a parent, a member of a sports team or religious community.
如果我们花时间反思一下，或许就会认识到：除了工作，我们还可以认定自己是朋友、配偶、儿子或女儿、父亲或母亲、运动队或宗教团体的一员。
We may recognise that we feel and act differently in these roles and relationships than we do at work.
我们也许会认识到，自己在这些角色和关系中的感受与行为，和在工作中有所不同。
The passive daughter becomes an assertive leader at work.
被动的女儿到了工作中，会变成果敢自信的领导者。
Furthermore, our identities at work are not static.
此外，我们在工作中的身份并非一成不变。
They change over time.
它们会随着时间的推移而改变。
I myself have been a shop assistant, a waitress, a student, a graduate, and a clinical psychologist.
我本人就当过店员、女服务员、学生、毕业生，如今则是一名临床心理学家。
At each stage my ability to adapt to and develop my career identity has been crucial to my wellbeing.
在每个阶段，我适应和发展职业身份的能力，对我的身心健康都至关重要。
Whilst we like to eliminate uncertainty in our lives, at some level we have to manage uncertainty, especially in today’s volatile and ever-shifting job market.
尽管我们都希望消除生活中的不确定性，但在某种程度上，我们不得不应对不确定性，尤其是在当今动荡不定、变化不断的就业市场中。
How we see ourselves is central to the issue of our identity.
我们如何看待自己，是身份问题的核心所在。
When we tell ourselves “I’m good at starting projects but not so great at seeing them through” it can become part of our belief system.
我们对自己说“我擅长启动项目，却不太擅长把项目进行到底”，这句话就可能成为我们信念体系的一部分。
But if you have the unfortunate experience of an enforced job change, you will need to examine those beliefs to see how grounded in reality they are.
但如果你不幸经历了被迫换工作，就需要审视那些信念，看看它们在多大程度上立足于现实。
You will be required to ask yourself how helpful these beliefs are and consider personal change.
你必须问问自己这些信念有多大帮助，并考虑做出自我改变。
We can change our beliefs, behaviours and emotional experience at any time through experimentation, practice and conscious self-discipline.
我们可以随时通过尝试、练习和有意识的自律，来改变自己的信念、行为和情绪体验。
In an age where career progression may lead us into new sectors, it is ever more important to challenge our sense of self and explore whether we can create a new experience of our identity by changing the beliefs we hold about ourselves in order to expand our career options.
在这个职业发展可能把我们带入新行业的时代，挑战自我认知、探索能否通过改变我们对自己所持的信念来创造一种新的身份体验，以拓宽自己的职业选择，就显得愈发重要。
Ultimately it is you who define who you are.
归根结底，界定你是谁的，正是你自己。
You are only your job if you let it be so.
只有你自己允许，工作才会成为你的全部。